Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period



Oracle Certified Associate seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Oracle PLSQL, SQL, Data modeling, RDBMS, Postgresql, Performance Tuning, Quality Management, ETL, Mongo DB, SVN, Agile



Current Designation: Senior Associate

Current Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Current Location: Coimbatore

Pref. Location: Coimbatore, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Development, Application Development, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Oracle PLSQL,SQL,Data modeling,RDBMS,Postgresql,Performance Tuning,Quality Management,ETL,MongoDB,SVN, Agile

Development,

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

12 years of experience with expertise as Oracle PL/SQL Developer in areas of Application software development and maintenance in Oracle environment using Client/Server

Good understanding of Business Functionality in the Telecom, Healthcare and Retail domain.

Created Packages, Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Partitions, Cursors

Worked on both water fall and Agile Scrum models.

Created Schema, Users, Tables, Constraints, Indexes, Triggers, Privileges, Roles, Cursors, Ref Cursors, User Profiles, anonymous blocks, directories, sequences, and synonyms.

Granted resources, privileges and roles to users

Tuned SQL queries using EXPLAIN PLAN, Hints and SQL*Plus Auto trace report for query optimization Used SQL*Loader, Import/Export, UTL FILE, DBMS XMLQUERY, DBMS PIPE and other Oracle built-in packages Automated SQL*Loader to load the data from the flat files

Performance Tuning of Oracle Applications using TKPROF

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd as Senior Associate

Aug 2011 to Till Date

Glencore Agriculture :- is a global leader in the sourcing, handling, processing and marketing of agricultural commodities and products with operations in more than 35 countries and over 13,000 employees, they create value for producers at origin and customers at destination.

Analyze PowerBuilder code and understand the business logic.

Collaborating with stakeholders understanding the requirements.

Creation of technical document for each page in PowerBuilder application.

Understand the business logic behind each PowerBuilder screens.

Develop oracle objects like packages, triggers, procedure and functions migrating the PowerBuilder functionality into oracle objects.

Performance tuning of oracle objects.

Supporting SIT and UAT.

Versioning the oracle code using Star team.

Took complete responsibility of each deliverables and ensure to complete the project within the planned Timeline Report project status and progress of the project to the clients on regular basis during our scrum calls.

Anthem Inc. is an American Health insurance company having its operation across 14 States. External sales compensation system is a compensation system for Anthem where External Agent commissions are computed and loaded into oracle tables. The Policy Premium information flows from various source like FACETS, COMPASS, CHIP and CS90 in file formats. The files are processed and loaded into oracle tables. The Agent commissions are computed biweekly and stored in oracle tables for payment.

Gathering and understanding the business requirements

Understand the compensation logic of ESCS system.

Study the data model of ISCS system to which the Agent commission has to be migrated.

Developed packages, procedures and tables to extract, transform and store the data as per the target system format. Involved in performance tuning the Objects and complex queries.

Managed a team of 5 members and made them understand the business requirement and functionality and helped them in technical aspects.

Supported SIT and UAT and fixed issues.

Took complete responsibility of each deliverables and ensure to complete the project within the planned Timeline Report project status and progress of the project to the clients on regular basis during our scrum calls.

Cigna In :- . The provider and cost information flow from two source systems, namely Arvato and Truven in file format. The files are loaded into Oracle staging tables through Data stage. The provider and cost information are processed in oracle system through batch process applying the business rules and the data is transformed into JSON and IDOL format. This process is a weekly process. The JSON and IDOL data are loaded into MongoDB and IDOL servers respectively. The Cigna application hits the IDOL servers and Mongo DB to access the provider and cost information.

Closely work with business analysts to understand the user stories.

Creation of technical document for the stories.

Create/Modify stored procedures and Packages as per the requirement.

Involved in Unit testing the changes.

Involved in performance tuning of the packages.

Supported the project during Delivery testing and SIT phase.

Will ensure quality, promptness, take the complete responsibility of each deliverable and ensure to complete the project within the planned Timeline

Report project status and progress to Customer on a regular basis during our Agile Scrum calls.

Cultivate domain knowledge to the team.

HealthNet:- Provider Directory Modernization program aims to build the directories for Commercial, Medicare and Duals provider's automatically. The directories are otherwise called BOOKS which are nothing but PDF files containing provider information's. The provider directories are given on-demand to the business.

Closely work with my onsite counterpart to understand their requirements.

Discuss the new requirement with the Clients and document the same.

Creation of High level and Low level solution documents.

Creation of oracle objects

Tata Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd as IT Analyst

Jun 2006 to Jul 2011

Qwest provides Internet and voice call features, west MSN workflow is a provisioning system which provisions HSI (High speed Internet) customers and maintain customer, product and equipment and order level information for Qwest HSI customers. The customer places an order over phone which hits Consulting Plus - Ordering system. The ordering system will provide the input to DSL Workflow is XML format. This XML contains the customer information, type of service requested, product information etc which is picked up by DSL Workflow Launches a set of tasks with a predefined order for provisioning the customer.

Responsible for Solving issues which gets raised in form of tickets.

Clearing manuals-which arise when an order fails.

Attending Audits

Carrying out reconciliations.

PREPAID Sep 2006 - Aug 2010

Prepaid service launched by Tata Tele Services using CDMA Technology with RUIM is a prestigious launch by the Tata's. AIS (Activation Information System) serve as the base system for prepaid provisioning. OTAF (Over the Air Functioning), which is a Motorola product, interacts with AIS for programming the handset with the Mobile Identification Number. As and when the request comes to AIS, TIBCO will pull the details for activations and frames the request format and sends them to SAS, which in turn sends them to Switch. The status of activation is back updated into AIS via TIBCO. The required details are replicated in CRM and POS through TIBCO interface. AlS also used to do the bulk activations as and when required. The Bulk activations (pre-activation in Delinquent mode) are done only for RUIM. The Subscriber is activated only when the dealer sends the sms to activate, the dealer will do this only if he gets the required documents from the customer. For the sms activation the integration between the sms apps and AIS is done through Tibco. AIS store the information about MDNs and their attributes, Starter Packs and their attributes, Activations and their status, MINs and their attributes. Prepaid TTSL has launched HSIA and EVDO for high speed internet access.

Primarily responsible for delivering the CRs (Change Request) to the Client.

Has looked into every aspect of the requirements and identified if any potential issues that may arise out of the change requested by the Business.

Involved in the design, coding and testing of various enhancements pertaining to AIS through Change requests. Involved in automating batch processes in AIS.

Served Ad-hoc requests originating from clients

Have been a part of the AISRAC migration activity.

Played a Key Role in the design, coding and testing of the various functional aspects in the GSM implementation.

Gained end to end domain knowledge on telecom business.

Prepared the knowledge base for numerous business functionalities.

Transferred the knowledge to the peers and groomed the new members coming into the team.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Anna University, Chennai in 2006

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Oracle Certified Associate

IT Skills

| Skill Name | Version | Last Used | Experience |
|---|---------|-----------|------------|
| Windows, Oracle, PostgreSQL, Java | | | |
| (Plsql), UNIX (Shell Scripting) | | | |
| MongoDB, Waterfall, Agile(Scrum) | | | |
| SQL Developer, TOAD, Erwin, (VSS),GIT | | | |
| SAP Crystal Report, Tortoise svn | | | |
| Toad Data modeler, Eclipse, Informatica | | | |

Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English | Proficient | | | |
| Tamil | Proficient | | | |
| Kannada | Proficient | | | |

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time